The Gaussian blur a seemingly complex effect is
actually quite simple It's all about averaging imagine
you have an image represented by a grid
of pixels Each pixel has a value and
blurring involves averaging the value of each pixel
with its neighbors Let's focus on one pixel
and its immediate neighbors The new value of
this pixel is calculated by taking the average
of its current value and the values of
its neighbors This averaging process is applied to
all pixels in the image Repeatedly applying this
averaging process smooths out sharp transitions and reduces
noise That's how a Gaussian blur works a
simple yet powerful averaging technique